<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bible Doctrine - R.B. Thieme Jr. Teachings</title>
    <link>https://bible-doctrine.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bible Doctrine - R.B. Thieme Jr. Teachings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bible-doctrine.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>David Lesson 002</title>
      <link>https://bible-doctrine.com/david/lesson-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bible-doctrine.com/david/lesson-002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-lesson-002&#34;&gt;David Lesson 002&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Word of God is alive and powerful, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing even to the dividing asunder of the soul and the spirit of the joints and the marrow, and is a critic of thoughts and intents of the heart. All scripture is God-breathed and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness, that the man of God might be mature, thoroughly furnished unto all good works. Study to show thyself approved unto God a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the Word of Truth. Open the Word of Truth this evening to 1 Samuel, chapter 16, 1 Samuel, chapter 16. We resume our study at verse 13. 1 Samuel 16, verse 13. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some of the most idiotic telephone calls you can imagine. Someone called and wanted to know how long we were going to have our message tonight, and I told them, if you&amp;rsquo;re worried about that, don&amp;rsquo;t come. Secondly, people who allegedly come to Baraka Church wanted to know if there was anything going on tonight, and I told them, no, nothing new, and I do want to tell you something else. Every now and then we get someone who hears we&amp;rsquo;re having a conference here who is a Christian moocher. These kind of people will pray upon your sympathy and make you think that they&amp;rsquo;re really in sad shape, and only you can help them. If some panhandling, mooching Christian comes up to you and says, I&amp;rsquo;m brother so-and-so, forget it, I try to protect the sheep around here as much as possible, but I cannot stand at all the doors and filter out some of the panhandlers that come through. So every now and then you have to be alert when we have these conferences so that you don&amp;rsquo;t get taken in by someone of this sort. There will not be a tour of TNP Saturday night. It was announced, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be. So we can cancel that on the agenda. Now in preparation for the study of the Word of God this evening, the next few moments are devoted to silent prayer. The objective is to give you privacy of the priesthood in order that you might rebound if necessary, and in order that you might be filled with the Spirit, which is the only approach to the Word of God. The Lord once said to Moses, take off your shoes, you stand on holy ground. In this dispensation, it&amp;rsquo;s be filled with the Spirit that you might take in the Word of God. The only holy ground we have is the canon of Scripture, and it is impossible, no matter how smart you are, even if you&amp;rsquo;re a genius, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to take in the Word of God. Unless the Holy Spirit, who indwells you, also controls your life. This can only be accomplished by being in fellowship. This can only be fulfilled by the rebound technique. And therefore, to give you privacy for preparation for the study of the Word of God, let us pray. We are grateful to thee, Heavenly Father, that ours is the privilege of spending this holiday around the Word of God. Every day that we are consistent in taking in the Word, this is just that much closer to the super-grace life and to the capacity for happiness which belongs to the super-grace believer. Now, Father, we recognize that this is the day when families get together, and this is the day when many people who do not have families are lonely and left out. We thank thee that we can gather around the Word of God tonight where no one is left out, where no one is excluded. And so, as we fellowship in the Word of God tonight, whatever many have missed by way of the family gatherings or by way of eating or dining or having fellowship with someone today, we pray that God the Holy Spirit will provide for them, as for all of us, that manna from heaven, that bread of life which is so important in our daily walk. To that end, we ask that God the Holy Spirit will sanctify this spiritual food to the nourishment of our souls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Have Seen A King</title>
      <link>https://bible-doctrine.com/david/lesson-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bible-doctrine.com/david/lesson-001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-lesson-001&#34;&gt;David Lesson 001&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-the-life-of-david&#34;&gt;Introduction to the life of David&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-the-super-grace-life&#34;&gt;Introduction to the Super Grace Life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;failures-of-samuel-and-saul&#34;&gt;Failures of Samuel and Saul&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-samuel-161-12&#34;&gt;1 Samuel 16:1-12&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-7870&#34;&gt;Psalm 78:70&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-sam-78&#34;&gt;2 Sam 7:8&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Word of God is alive and powerful, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing even to the dividing asunder of the soul and the spirit of the joints and the marrow, and is a critic of thoughts and intents of the heart. All Scripture is God-breathed and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness, that the man of God might be mature, thoroughly furnished unto all good works. Study to show thyself approved unto God, a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the Word of Truth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
